Guide to the Carol Liberman papers, 1983-2014 MS 767
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Carol Liberman papers
1983-2014
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Liberman, Carol
MS 767
.25 Linear Feet 1 box
This collection includes books, correspondence, newspaper clippings, newsletters, photographs, and a speech given by Liberman that document some of her forty-plus- years of teaching.
Biographical / Historical
Carol Liberman graduated Phi Beta Kappa from the University of Georgia and began her teaching career at age 20. She tought in Atlanta before moving to Houston in 1967. In Houston she joined the Teacher Corps, earned a M.Ed., and spent six years working to desegregate Houston public schools before moving on to teach at the Jewish Secondary school, which later became Emory Wiener where she taught English and History for 16 years.
In 1993, she began teaching at the Hebrew Academy, which later became Robert M. Beren Academy, where she taught for 21 years before retiring after over 48 years as an educator.
Outside of teaching, one of Liberman's great loves is baseball. When she moved to Houston in 1969 she became a die-hard Houston Astros fan, and was selected to represent the Houston Astros as one of "People's All-star teachers" in 2014 and was recognized at that year's MLB All-Star Game at Target Field in Minnesota.
Excerpted from: http://jhvonline.com/retiring-day-school-teacher-a-finalist-for-allstar-honor-p17418-102.htm
Scope and Contents
Books, correspondence, newspaper clippings, newsletters, photographs, and a speech document parts of Liberman's forty-plus years in the classroom. Of particular interest is a speech Liberman gave at a ceremony recognizing her first ten years teaching at I. Weiner Jewish Secondary School of Houston and a cookbook organized by the Hebrew Academy PTO which contains favorite recipes of parents, teachers, and staff.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection have been arranged in six series as follows: Series I: Books; Series II: Correspondence; Series III: News Clippings; Series IV: Newsletters; Series V: Photographs; Series VI: Speeches
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research. Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Carol Liberman donated the papers in July of 2018. The papers came from home and office.
Related Materials
MS 731 Emery-Weiner School collection
Index Terms
Subjects
Education
Document Types
newsletters; clippings (information artifacts); speeches; photographs; personal correspondence
Subjects (Corporations)
I. Weiner Jewish Secondary School of Houston; Robert M. Beren Academy
- Series I: Books, 1978-1993
  - Hebrew Academy PTO cookbook, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - I. Weiner Tenth Anniversary program, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - I. Weiner yearbook, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Mirage Literary journals, I. Weiner (3), 1983-1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series II: Correspondence, 2006
  - Note from Laura Bush, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Note from Kinky Friedman, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series III: News Clippings, 1991-2004
  - News clipping honoring Liberman as an educator, 1991-2004 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series IV: Newsletters, 2010
  - Robert M. Beren Academy newsletter, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series V: Photographs, 2002-2004
  - Hebrew Academy group photograph, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Beren Academy trip to Washington D.C. group photo (2), 2002-2004 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series VI: Speeches, 1988
  - Speech to I. Weiner: "A Decade of Service", 1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)